Guide to the Jean Kilbourne Papers, 1918-2014 and undated RL.10982
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jean Kilbourne papers
1918-2014 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Kilbourne, Jean
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.10982
70 Linear Feet
Media critic, feminist author and documentary filmmaker based in Massachusetts. Collection spans 1918-2014 and includes: clippings; tear sheets; correspondence; research reports and other printed materials; slides and slide presentation texts; audiovisual materials in multiple formats including 8mm and 16mm films, audio and video cassettes; book drafts and research files used for teaching and production of Kilbournes books and films. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History and the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History & Culture.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1918-2014 and includes: clippings; tear sheets; correspondence; research reports and other printed materials; slides and slide presentation texts; audiovisual materials in multiple formats including 8mm and 16mm films, audio and video cassettes; book drafts and research files used for teaching and production of Kilbournes books and films. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History and the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History & Culture.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, the Litigation Files Series is closed to research until further notice. In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Book Files; Clippings; Correspondence; Educational Programs; Litigation Files; Personal Files; Research Files; Teaching Files; Print Advertisements; Slides and Slide Presentations; Printed Materials; Audiovisual Materials; and Large-format Materials.
Historical note
Biographical timeline
1943 Jan. 4 Born, Junction City, Kan.
1964 B.A., English, Wellesley College
1969-1972 Teacher, Norwall High School, Norwall, Mass.
1972 M.A., Education, Boston University
1972-1975 Professor, Emerson College
1979 Film, Killing Us Softly: Advertising's Image of Women
1980 PhD, Education, Boston University
1984-On Senior Scholar, Wellesley Centers for Women
1982 Film, Calling the Shots
1987 Film, Still Killing Us Softly
1992 Film, Pack of Lies
1993 National Advisory Council on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism
1994 Film, The Killing Screens
1995 Film, Sexual Harassment Film, Slim Hopes: Advertising and the Obsession with Thinness
1996 Film, The End of Education
1999 Book, Deadly Persuasion; republished 2000 as Can't Buy My Love
2000 Film, Killing Us Softly 3
2004 Honorary Doctorate, Westfield State College Film, Spin the Bottle: Sex, Lies and Alcohol Film, Deadly Persuasion: Advertising of Alcohol and Tobacco
2008 Film, So Sexy So Soon: The New Sexualized Childhood and What Parents Can Do to Protect Their Kids
2010 Film, Killing Us Softly 4
Provenance
The Jean Kilbourne Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2014
Feminism and mass media; Feminism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Sexism -- United States; Media literacy; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- Alcoholic beverages; Feminism -- United States -- History; Advertising; Audiocassettes; 8mm; Videocassettes; Tear sheets; Sexism in mass media; 16mm; Clippings (information artifacts); Feminism -- United States; Advertising and children -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Advertising -- Cigarettes -- United States; Advertising -- Consumer psychology; Advertising and youth; Advertising -- Beer; Documentary films -- United States; Advertising and women; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Kilbourne, Jean; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Book Files, 1976-1999 and undated; 7 boxes
  - Alcohol-related, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Addiction, 1991-1999 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Advertising, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Alcoholism as Worship (Nancy Holloway), 1989 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Children, 1990-1999; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Clippings, 1991-1998 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--College students, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Crime, 1996-1999; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Effects of advertising, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol--Heavy drinking, 1996-1999 (Box 2)
  - Articles--Corporate crime, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Articles--Gambling, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Articles--Individual actions (boycotts, etc.), 1997-1999 (Box 2)
  - Articles--Miscellaneous, 1995-1999; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Articles--Normalizing greed, 1986-1999 (Box 2)
  - Automobiles--Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Book cover (Deadly Persuasion), undated (Box 2)
  - Book proposal--G.K. Hall, 1984; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Book proposals (old), undated (Box 2)
  - Ch. 13 advertisements referred to, undated (Box 2)
  - CH. 13 articles, 1996-1999 (Box 2)
  - Ch. 13 articles to consider, undated (Box 2)
  - Cigarettes (Ch.), undated (Box 3)
  - Corporate power, undated (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--D.C. Heath, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--G.K. Hall, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Henry Holt, 1996-1998 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Miscellaneous agents, 1989-1994 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Publishers, 1976-1994 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Re book, 1998-2003 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence--Susan Heath, 1996-1998 (Box 3)
  - Deadly Persuasion (draft), undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Deadly Persuasion (draft), 1999; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Dissertation article, undated (Box 4)
  - Editorial information, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Environment--Alcohol and college campuses, 1995-1999; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Environmental approach--General, undated (Box 5)
  - Environmental approach--Tobacco, undated (Box 5)
  - Girls--Articles, 1995-1999 (Box 5)
  - Girls--Body image (Ch. 6), 1996-1999; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Girls--Thinness, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Global issues (for introduction), 1997-1999 (Box 5)
  - Guggenheim application, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Guilford references, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Introduction, 1992-1999 (Box 5)
  - Introduction, 1992-1997 (Box 6)
  - Introduction--Notes, undated (Box 6)
  - Introduction--Versions, undated (Box 6)
  - Kaiser Family Foundation publications (Children Now), 1996; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Killing Us Softly--Free Press, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Killing Us Softly--Hanley & Belfus, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Killing Us Softly--Henry Holt, 1996 (Box 6)
  - List of ads by chapter (Deadly Persuasion), 1999 (Box 6)
  - List of ads in the book, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Marketing the Myth (prospectus), 1978 (Box 6)
  - Notes, undated (Box 6)
  - Notes on the book, undated (Box 6)
  - Obsession with weight (Ch.), undated (Box 7)
  - Page proofs and corrections, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Publicity--Free Press, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Solutions (Ch. 13), undated (Box 7)
  - Solutions--Counter-advertising, 1989-1999 (Box 7)
  - Solutions--Media literacy, 1990-1994 (Box 7)
  - Solutions--Political, undated (Box 7)
  - Solutions--Taking on corporations, undated (Box 7)
  - Solutions--Treatment, 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Still Killing Us Softly (Guilford Press), 1991-1994 (Box 7)
  - Tyranny of the ideal image, undated (Box 7)
  - Wellesley Centers for Women Report, 1995-1997 (Box 7)
- Clippings, 1977-2000 and undated; 2 boxes
  - Clipping file (chronological), 1977-1984; 7 folders (Box 8)
  - Clipping file (chronological), 1985-2000 and undated; 17 folders (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1977-2000 and undated; 3 boxes
  - Addiction/prevention/recovery, 1991-1998 (Box 10)
  - Advertisers, 1981-1992 (Box 10)
  - Alcoholism/health organizations, 1983-1995 (Box 10)
  - Brazil, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Business schools and organizations, 1979-1996 (Box 10)
  - Canada, 1979-1984 (Box 10)
  - Colleges, 1977-2000 (Box 10)
  - Community and political groups, 1980-1998 (Box 10)
  - Community groups, 1980-1997 (Box 10)
  - Community/Women's groups, 1996-2000 (Box 10)
  - Feminist groups, 1979-1998 (Box 10)
  - Film inquiries, 1979-2000 (Box 10)
  - Foreign personal correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 11)
  - Government/Political, 1986-1993 (Box 11)
  - Killing Us Softly III, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Killing Us Softly, etc. as lecture titles, 1989-2000 (Box 11)
  - Letters linking Kilbourne with films, 1979-2000 (Box 11)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1977-1996 (Box 11)
  - Massachusetts, 1980-1989 (Box 11)
  - Media Education Foundation, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Media literacy, 1998 (Box 11)
  - Medical and health professions, 1978-1998 (Box 11)
  - Medical/Public health, 1990-1999 (Box 11)
  - Midwest, 1979-1989 (Box 11)
  - New England, 1979-1988 (Box 11)
  - New York/New Jersey, 1980-1988 (Box 11)
  - Northwest, 1979-1981 (Box 11)
  - Pennsylvania, 1984-1986 (Box 11)
  - Personal, 1979-1999; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Private and public schools, 1978-2000; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Religious schools and organizations, 1981-1986 (Box 12)
  - Reviews, 1979-1987 (Box 12)
  - Sample letters about lectures, 1993-2000 (Box 12)
  - Schools, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
  - The South, 1980-1993 (Box 12)
  - The Southwest, 1981-1983 (Box 12)
  - Texas, 1979-1987 (Box 12)
  - Variations of "Killing Us Softly", 1980-2000 (Box 12)
  - Virgin Islands, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Washington, D.C., 1981-1988 (Box 12)
  - West coast/California, 1980-1993 (Box 12)
- Educational Programs, 1986-2002; 4 boxes
  - Communities Take Charge--Citizens Action Handbook on Alcohol and Tobacco Billboard Advertising, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Communities Take Charge--Directory of Resources, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Communities Take Charge--Manual for the Prevention of Alcohol and Other Drug Problems among Youth, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Communities Take Charge--Marketing Booze to Blacks, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Communities Take Charge--Marketing Disease to Hispanice, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Flash Point: Life Skills through the Lens of Media Literacy, undated (Box 13)
  - Flash Point II: Close-Up on Civil Rights, undated (Box 13)
  - Flash Point III: Close-Up on Underage Drinking, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Flash Point IV: Close-Up on Internet Intelligence, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Images About Alcohol (FACE: Facing Alcohol Concerns through Education), 1993; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Media Matters--Substance Abuse: The Influence of the Media, undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Medienkoffer--Das Frauenbild in den Medien [Broos et al] (Media Kit: The Image of Women in the Media), undated (Box 14)
  - Of Wine and Women (S.C. Dept. of Alcohol), 1986 (Box 14)
  - Of Wine and Women II (S.C. Dept. of Alcohol), 1993 (Box 15)
  - Thinking About Drinking (David Freudberg) listener guide [tapes removed to Audiovisual Materials Series], 1988 (Box 15)
  - AdSmarts Module A: Media and Advertising, 1993 (Box 15)
  - AdSmarts Module B: Alcohol Advertising, 1993 (Box 15)
  - AdSmarts Module C: Tobacco Advertising, 1993 (Box 15)
  - AdSmarts Module D: Media, Alcohol and Tobacco Advertising, 1993 (Box 15)
  - AdSmarts Module E: Media Action, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Beyond Blame: Challenging Violence in the Media, 1995 (Box 15)
  - Canada Cancer Society hazardous materials instruction kit (tobacco-related), undated (Box 15)
- Litigation Files [RESTRICTED], 1979-2002 and undated; 4 boxes
  Access Restrictions
  Materials in this series are closed to research until further notice
  - Cambridge Documentary Films litigation files, 2001-2002; 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Cambridge Documentary Films litigation files, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Advertising Alcohol, income, 1991-1997 (Box 17)
  - Calling the Shots, income, 1982-1993 (Box 17)
  - Cambridge film promotion examples, undated (Box 17)
  - Contracts, 1983-1991 (Box 17)
  - Copyright violation, 2000-2001 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1980-2000; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Correspondence--Bromberg & Sunstein, 2000-2001 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence--Palmer & Dodge, 1995-2000 (Box 18)
  - Court documents, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Court of Appeals--Joint Record Appendix, 2001 (Box 18)
  - Discovery, 2001 (Box 18)
  - Film festivals, 1981-1988 (Box 18)
  - Income notes, 1979-1986 (Box 18)
  - Insurance, 1999-2001 (Box 18)
  - Jean Kilbourne promotional posters, undated (Box 19)
  - Killing Us Softly, income, 1979-1993; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Legal bills, 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - Media Education Foundation promotion examples, undated (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000-2002 (Box 19)
  - Promotional expense receipts, 1985-1994 (Box 19)
  - Promotional posters, undated (Box 19)
  - Resource lists, undated (Box 19)
  - Still Killing Us Softly, expenses, 1986-1987 (Box 19)
  - Still Killing Us Softly, income, 1987-1999 (Box 19)
  - Subdistribution contracts, 1982-1988 (Box 19)
- Personal Files, 1960-1983 and undated; 1 boxes
  - Doctoral dissertation (Boston University): The Changing Image of Females and Males in Television Commercials, 1980; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Graduation, Boston University, 1972 (Box 20)
  - Graduation, Hingham High School, 1960 (Box 20)
  - Master's Thesis (Boston University): A Practical Guide to a Student-Centered Film Study Course, 1971; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - NOW Woman of the Year, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Photograph, Kilbourne lecturing, undated (Box 20)
  - Units on Shakespeare (includes Kilbourne's student papers from Wellesley), 1963-1968 (Box 20)
  - Wedding announcement, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Wellesley--Kilbourne student papers, undated (Box 20)
  - Women's studies papers by Kilbourne, undated (Box 20)
  - Satin Jacket, The Naked Truth 1979-1980 World Tour (Box 66)
- Research Files, 1948-2003 and undated; 34 boxes
  - Addiction--Behind Bars: Substance Abuse and America's Prison Population, 1998 (Box 21)
  - Addiction--Celebrities, 1979-1991 (Box 21)
  - Addiction--Shopping, 1980-2000 (Box 21)
  - Addiction--Society, 1988-1992 (Box 21)
  - Addiction--Women, 1985 (Box 21)
  - Addiction--Work, 1979-1991 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Advertiser response to criticism, 1967-1980 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--As addiction, 1981-1991 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--As propaganda, 1973-1982 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Book reviews, 1979-1985 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Celebrities, 1981-1990 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Education, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Effect on children, 1975-1995 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Effectiveness, 1979-1993 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Ethics, 1970-1984 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--Frequency, 1980-1998 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--General, 1980-1991 (Box 21)
  - Advertising--History, 1978-1989 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Illusion and deception, 1978-1994 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--In schools, 1985-1999 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Industry, 1988-1995 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Influence, 1966-1983 (Box 22)
  - Advertising Language and Ideology (Vestergaard & Schroder), 1985 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Positive approaches, 1978 and undated (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Public opinion, 1979-1985 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Regulation, 1989-1992 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Regulation--Cross-cultural, 1976-1990 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Regulation--First amendment, 1980-1988 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Regulation--Self-regulation, 1980-1981 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Regulation--Truth in advertising, 1975-1988 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Research on effects, 1982-1995 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Subliminal, 1970-1999 (Box 22)
  - Advertising--Subliminal, 1970-1999 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Targeting children, 1978-2000 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Athletes/celebrities, 1979-1989 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Comparative, 1980 and undated (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Emotional, 1980 and undated (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--General, 1980-1986 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Image, 1979-1989 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Language, 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Music and jingles, 1978-1983 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Packaging and point-of-purchase, 1979-1981 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Positioning, 1972-1980 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Production effects, 1978-1981 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Techniques--Tie-ins, 1982-1991 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Ubiquity, 1978-1999 (Box 23)
  - Advertising--Women--Cartoons and jokes, 1978-1992 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Absolut, 1989-1991 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Accidents, 1979-1987 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Advertising debates, 1985-1992 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Advertising effects, 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--African-Americans, 1978-1991 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Alanon/Alateen, 1973-1978 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Alcoholic mothers, 1981-1994 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Alcoholism as disease, 1984-1989 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Alcoholism in Japan, 1978 (Box 23)
  - Alcohol--Almost All You Ever Wanted to Know About Alcohol, 1978 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Anheuser-Busch testimony, 1990 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Autosports and driving, 1986-1991 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Birth defects/Fetal Acohol Syndrome, 1977-1990 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Black college students, 1994 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Campus crime, 1988-1993 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Canada, 1985 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Cartoons and jokes, 1979-1992 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Child abuse, 1990-1996 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Children of alcoholics, 1975-1991; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--Codependence, 1979-1991 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--College newspapers, 1979-1990 (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--College programs, undated; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--College students, 1982-1999; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Alcohol--College women, 1987-1995 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Consumption, 1979-1988 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Consumption habits (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Controlled drinking, 1976-1977 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Cross-cultural, 1972-1980 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Cyberspace/Internet, 1995 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Dangerous Promises, 1993 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Designated drivers, 1990-1999 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Disabled, 1980-1991 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Drinking age, 1985 and undated (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Drinking and driving, 1971-1994 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Education (responsible drinking), 1977-1991 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Elderlly, 1982-1988 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Europe, 1980 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Expectant fathers, 1981-1990 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Families of Alcoholics, 1976-1993; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Feminist critique of 12-step programs, 1989-1992 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Feminist critique of codependence, 1989-1991 (Box 25)
  - Alcohol--Gambling, 1986-1996 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Gays, 1979-1984 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Health messages in advertisements, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Hispanics, 1980 and undated (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Imaginary peers, 1986-1997 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--In films, 1983-1989 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Industry, 1984-1993 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Industry influence, 1988-2000 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Institute of Medicine, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--International advertising, 1979-1985 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Jews, 1980-1982 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Join Together, 1992 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Macho/Power, 1974-1989 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--"Magic potion", 1990 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Market research, 1975-1986 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Marketing, 1981-1985; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to alcoholics, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to blacks, 1987-1992 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to college students, 1990-1996 (Box 26)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to Gays, 1984-1993 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to Hispanics, 1984-1990 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to minorities, 1994 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to women, 1982-1992 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Marketing to youth, 1987-1998; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Media consultation, 1979-1988 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Minorities, 1980-1994 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Minority women, undated (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Moderate drinking and health, 1983-2000 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Music and bars, 1979-1980 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Music and youth, 1979-1991 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Native Americans, 1980 and undated (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Nursing mothers, 1979-1991 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Nutrition, 1983-1989 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Patriotism/Values, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Policy, 1975-1995; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Alcohol--Popular culture, 1980-1982 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Posters, 1982 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Pregnancy, 1990-1994 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Prevention, 1976-1989 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Print advertisement examples, undated (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Problem drinking, 1983-1991 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Promotion, 1981-1992 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Public opinion, 1990 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Regulation, 1987-1990 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Research, 1963-1996; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Risky behavior, 1987-1990 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Server training, 1984-1986 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Sex, 1985-1999 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Sex and sexism, 1982-1991 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Sex differences, 1976-1988 (Box 28)
  - Alcohol--Soviet Union/Russia, 1984 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Sports, 1983-1996 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Spring break, 1984-1991 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Spuds Mackenzie, 1987-1988 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Surgeon General workshop, 1988-1989 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Talk shows, 1982 and undated (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Targeting, 1983-1991 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Taxes, 1981-1993 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Television, 1980-1990; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Third World, undated (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Underage drinking, 1985-1991 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--University, 1982-1988 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--University policies, 1984-1993 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--University liability, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Vs. other drugs, 1987-1993 (Box 29)
  - Alcohol--Violence and crime, 1979-1997 (Box 30)
  - Alcohol--Violence and sports, 1985-1987 (Box 30)
  - Alcohol--Warning labels, 1980-1994 (Box 30)
  - Alcohol--Women, 1978-1996; 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Alcohol--Women--Sexuality, 1982-1996 (Box 30)
  - Alcohol--Women--Treatment, 1982-1994 (Box 30)
  - Alcohol--Workplace, 1988-1991 (Box 30)
  - Alcohol--Youth, 1974-1995; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Alternatives, 1980 (Box 30)
  - Capitalism, 1980 and undated (Box 31)
  - Class, 1977-1991 (Box 31)
  - Class--Exploitation of third world workers, 1978-1996 (Box 31)
  - Class--Poverty, 1984-1990 (Box 31)
  - Class--The rich, 1979-1986 (Box 31)
  - Consumer product safety, 1979-1996 (Box 31)
  - Consumerism, 1977-1994 (Box 31)
  - Corporate dumping, 1980-1982 (Box 31)
  - Corporate public relations, 1979-1986 (Box 31)
  - Corporations, 1975-1996 (Box 31)
  - Corporations--Influence, 1981-1992 (Box 31)
  - Crime, 1985-1994 (Box 31)
  - Crime--Corporate, 1979-1994 (Box 31)
  - Crime--Youth, 1983 (Box 31)
  - Death and grief, 1977-1997 (Box 31)
  - Disability, 1980-1988 (Box 31)
  - Drugs, 1980-1990 (Box 31)
  - Drugs--Anti-drug, 1987-1991 (Box 31)
  - Drugs--Caffeine, 1980-1984 (Box 31)
  - Drugs--Cocaine, 1986-1990 (Box 31)
  - Drugs--Legalization debate, 1980-1995 (Box 31)
  - Drugs--Marijuana, 1989-1990 (Box 31)
  - Drugs--Partnership for a Drug Free America, 1990-1996 (Box 32)
  - Drugs--War on Drugs, 1986-1992 (Box 32)
  - Drugs--War on Drugs--Civil rights, 1986-1990 (Box 32)
  - Drugs--War on Drugs--Minorities and the inner city, 1982-1990 (Box 32)
  - Drugs--Women, undated (Box 32)
  - Election 94, 1994 (Box 32)
  - Feminism--Action strategies, 1978-2002 (Box 32)
  - Feminism--Androgeny, 1978-1980 (Box 32)
  - Feminism--Anger, 1978-1993 (Box 32)
  - Feminism--Articles about specific women, 1966-1977 (Box 32)
  - Feminism--Assertiveness training, 1978-1979 (Box 32)
  - Feminism--Athletics, 1980 (Box 32)
  - Feminism--Consciousness raising, 1980-1988 and undated; 2 folders (Box 32)